Encounters are mysterious! But the world is even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والعالم تلفّه طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today is a serious code! If adding doesn't work, try subtracting!
!اليوم شفرة مبتكرة! إذا لم ينفع الجمع، فجرّب الطرح
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Kaori, the daughter of the novelist Shinmei Nintaro,
،أتت كاوري، ابنة الروائيّ شينمي نينتارو
asked the old guy to find her parents who went missing.
لتطلب من العمّ البحث عن والديها المفقودين
They've been missing for two months,
اختفيا مذ شهرين
but the publisher still receives his manuscripts for his new series.
لكن لا يزال الناشر يتلقّى نصوص سلسلته الجديدة
We went straight to the publishing company.
توجّهنا لشركة النشر فوراً
We found several incomprehensible things about his manuscripts,
ورأينا هناك عدّة أشياء مبهمة في نصوصه
and they turned out to be a code calling for help!
!وتبيّن أنّها شفرة تطلب النجدة
Th-This is--!
!هـ-هذا
Just as I thought!
!كما ظننت
There's a message from Shinmei-sensei hidden in these lines!
توجد رسالة مخفية من شينمي سينسي !بين هذه الأسطر
Which makes it all fit: that provocative dedication,
في تلك الحالة، رسالة الإهداء الاستفزازية تلك وظهور المؤلّف في العمل
the author's appearance in the story, and the odd lines of dialogue!
!والحوار الغريب، كلّها متوافقة
But what is the goal of the person holding him and his wife captive?!
لكن ما هدف الفاعل الذي يحتجز !شينمي سينسي وزوجته؟
"The Mystery Writer Disappearance Case (Part 2)."
جريمة اختفاء مؤلف روايات الغموض (الجزء الثاني)
What is it? Did you realize something else?!
ما الأمر؟ هل أدركت شيئاً مُجدداً؟
It's nothing much, but...
...ليس بالأمر الكبير، لكن
Literature Era, Editing Department.
"أجل، دائرة التحرير في "عصر الأدب
All the first letters of dialogue are half--
...كلّ الأحرف الأولى من الحوار تشكّل نصف
Huh?! You figured out the code?!
ماذا؟ حللت الشفرة؟
Who are you?!
من أنت؟
Is something the matter?
أهنالك خطبٌ ما؟
A boy speaking Kansai dialect said he figured out the code
يقول شاب بلكنة كانساي أنّه حلّ الشفرة
so I should call the police here.
لذا عليّ استدعاء الشرطة هنا
Kansai dialect?
شاب بلكنة كانساي؟
Hello?
أجل، مرحباً؟
C'mon! Don't make me repeat myself, idiot! Just get the cops!
!اسمع! لا تجعلني أكرّر كلامي يا أحمق !اتّصل بالشرطة فوراً
Oh, you're already there! It's been awhile!
حضرة المفتّش، أنت موجودٌ هناك؟ مضى وقتٌ طويل
So, what's with you?
وما قصّتك بالضبط؟
The code. I cracked the code hidden in "Halves at the Top."
الشفرة، حللت الشفرة المخفيّة في ثنايا رواية "نصفان في القمّة" هذه
I pegged him as an angry old man after I first read his dedication,
عندما قرأتُ صفحة الإهداء لأوّل مرّة، ظننته عجوزاً مزعجاً
but I started to understand as I read
لكن تكوّنت لديّ الصورة بينما أقرأ
that Shinmei-han's dialogue in the story was all a code.
حوار المؤلف شينمي الذي ظهر في الرواية عبارة عن شفرة
It's a code?
حواره شفرة؟
Yeah... In other words, the dedication wasn't meant to provoke us.
أجل، أي أنّ الهدف من الإهداء لم يكن استفزاز القرّاء
He was asking someone to find the real message hidden in the novel!
بل كان يطلب من أحدهم قراءة الرسالة الحقيقيّة التي أخفاها في الرواية
I-I assume you've deciphered the coded message then?!
و-وأفترض أنّك حللت الرسالة المشفّرة إذاً؟
Yeah... the first part deciphers perfectly.
أجل، شفرة الجزء الأوّل مركّبة بسلاسة
The key was the novel's title: "Halves of the Top."
"كان المفتاح هو عنوان الرواية، "نصفان في القمّة
This means the letter at the top of each line is half of a full letter.
يعني هذا أنّ الرمز في أعلى كلّ سطر يمثل نصف حرف
Half of a full letter?
بدمج رمزين تحصل على حرف كامل؟
Reading with that in mind...
إذا قرأت من البداية ...واضعاً ذلك في الاعتبار
...you get "suke"...
،"دمج "تشيكارا" و"مي" يعطيك "سوكي
...then "ke"...
،"و"جو" و"إيتشي" يعطيانك "كي
...then "te"...
،"و"سي" و"إيتشي" يعطيان "تي
...and at the very end you get a "re."
"وفي النهاية تحصل على "ري "من "نو" و"إيتشي
The "ku" and "hoka" (other) before it are strange,
،كو" و"هوكا" قبل ذلك تحيراني"
but if "hoka" is meant to be a blank placeholder, you get "ku."
لكن إذا كان المقصود برمز "هوكا" هو اتركه في مكانٍ آخر"، فنضيف "كو" كما هي"
And if you read it all together...
...وإذا قرأتها سويّةً
"Ta su ke te ku re"...
..."تا-تا سو كي تي كو ري"
"Help us!" It's an SOS?!
!النجدة؟! إنّه نداء استغاثة؟
Yep... My guess is he's being held somewhere and forced to write.
أجل، أرجّح أنّ هذا الرجل محتجز في مكانٍ ومجبورٌ على الكتابة
I see... and that's why he used this method.
فهمت، لذا استعمل هذه الطريقة
He could get a message to his readers without his captor noticing.
يمكنه إيصال رسالة لقرّائه دون أن يلاحظ الفاعل
My mom was excited because it's the first new story in ten years,
كانت أمّي مسرورةً لأنّها أوّل ،قصّة جديدة لعشرة أعوام
so the perp is a crazed fan or someone planning to swipe the story.
فلا بدّ أنّ الفاعل معجب مجنون أو شخص ينوي سرقة أجور نصوص روائيّ شهير
Have these manuscripts been paid for yet?
هل دُفع أجر هذه النصوص؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد
He said he'd tell where to send the money when the story was done.
قال أنّه سيخبرنا بالمكان الذي سيرسل المال له عندما ينهي القصّة
Alright! Check all suspicious fan letters!
!حسناً، تفقّدوا كلّ رسائل المعجبين المشبوهة
Right!
!حاضر
Oh, but I haven't cracked the entire code yet!
!لكنّي لم أحلّ الشفرة بأسرها بعد
Hey! Inspector?! Inspector?!
!لحظة! حضرة المفتّش؟! حضرة المفتّش؟
Hey, Inspector! Hey! Where'd you go?! Quit playing around!
!حضرة المفتّش؟
Still, Hattori. About Shinmei-sensei's other lines...
...لكن يا هاتّوري، بشأن بقيّة أسطر شينمي سينسي
Oh! If it isn't Kudo! What're you doing there?!
!أنت يا كودو! ما الذي تفعله هناك؟
Nothing, I just happened to be here.
لا شيء، صادف أنّي أتيت
Yeah, I bet! You and me are a lot alike!
لا عجب، فنحن متشابهان كثيراً
We cross paths before we even know it!
تتقاطع طرقنا دون أن ننوي
Let's just get back to the code.
لنرجع لموضوع الشفرة
Hey! You should come to Osaka! I'll treat you to some great udon!
اسمع، ما رأيك بالقدوم لأوساكا؟ !سأدعوك لأكل أودون لذيذ قدرما تشاء
I can't stand the heavy flavor in Tokyo!
لا أستطيع تحمّل نكهة طوكيو الثقيلة
Bye.
سأقفل الخطّ
Sorry! Sorry! The code, right?!
آسف! آسف! نرجع للشفرة، صحيح؟
I managed to decipher the first lines of dialogue,
تمكّنتُ من فكّ شفرة السطر الأوّل
but "halves at the top" doesn't fit with the next ones.
لكن "نصفان في القمّة" لا توافق بقيّة الأسطر
Put together, you get...
...بترتيبها، ستحصل على
"Watashi hoka ka i he ima i haku re no tokoro han hito wa."
واتاشي هوكا كا إي هي إيما إي" "هاكو ري نو توكورو هان هيتو وا
Even if you remove the second "hoka," only "watashi" makes sense.
"حتّى لو أزلت "هوكا" الثانية، تبقى "واتاشي وحدها مفهومة القراءة
"He" and "ima" are iffy, but they don't combine into anything.
"ولم أستطع تشكيل كلمة بـ "هي" و"إما مهما حاولت من مرّات
It seems we still don't have all the pieces to this code.
يبدو أنّه لا تزال تنقصنا قطع لحلّ هذه الشفرة
Yeah... there has to be a big piece to this code hidden somewhere.
أجل، لا بدّ من وجود قطعة مهمّة متوارية في مكان عن أنظارنا
Hattori? What's wrong?
هاتّوري؟ ما الخطب؟
How stupid.
حماقة
If you're there, why should I puzzle over it from so far away?
إذا كنتَ هناك، فلمَ أكبّد نفسي عناء التفكير من مكاني البعيد؟
So the rest's all yours, Kudo!
لذا أترك الباقي لك يا كودو
Lemme know if you figure anything out! Good luck!
!اتّصل بي إذا وجدتَ شيئاً، بالتوفيق
H-Hey! Wait!
!أ-أنت! انتظر
Oh! That's right! Hattori-kun should know the rest of the code!
!صحيح! لا بدّ أنّ هاتّوري-كن يعرف بقيّة الشفرة
Damn!
!تبّاً
It wasn't me! He was the one who--!
...لم يكن أنا! كان هاتّوري-نيتشان من أقفل
Inspector... this is Tokyo.
حضرة المفتّش، هذه طوكيو
Let's forget about the Osaka boy and solve this ourselves!
!لنترك شاب أوساكا ذاك ونحلّ القضيّة بأنفسنا
Oh! Good call!
!معك حقّ
So, are you feeling sleepy?
إذاً، أبدأ النعاس يراودك؟
Huh? What do you mean?
ماذا؟ كيف يراودني النعاس؟
You know! When you always go, "Funya!" or "Hohe!"
أقصد عندما تصدر أصوات فونيا" و"هوهي" تلك"
Nope, nothing yet...
...كلا، ليس بعد
Oh, that's a shame.
هكذا إذاً، هذا مؤسف
Help us! Help us!
!النجدة! النجدة
Help us!
!النجدة
Dad... Mom...
...أبي... أمّي
Don't worry. I'm sure we'll find your mother and father.
لا تقلقي، أنا متأكّدة أنّنا سنجد أباك وأمّك
Don't give up.
لا تستسلمي
So let's use our heads, too.
لذا علينا التفكير بدورنا
Okay!
أجل
What is this code?!
ما هذه الشفرة؟
I also don't know who abducted them!
كما ما أجهله هو هويّة الفاعل الذي اختطفه
It would be natural to pay close attention to your captive's writings.
من البديهيات أن تنتبه لكتابات أسيرك
If the captor is a fan,
،إذا كان الفاعل أحد معجبيه
he'd clearly be suspicious of that atypical dedication and character.
فلا بدّ أن تثير رسالة الإهداء وظهور المؤلّف في العمل ريبته
He would've at least deciphered the first "help me" by now!
"يُفترض أنّه حلّ شفرة "النجدة الأولى منذ فترة على الأقل
In which case, he'd be after the manuscript payment.
في تلك الحالة، سيكون هدفه هو أجر النصوص
No, that can't be it.
كلا، لا يمكن ذلك
You wouldn't hold a person captive two whole months for that.
لن تحتجز أسيراً لشهرين كاملين مقابل ذلك
I can't figure out the captor's identity or this code!
!لا أستطيع فهم هدف الفاعل، أو الشفرة البتّة
Darn it!
!تبّاً
Hey! This is wrong!
!هذا خطأ
Using French to fancy things up is fine, but don't spell stuff wrong!
،لا بأس باستعمال اللغة الفرنسية للتأنّق لكن لا تخطئ في التهجئة
Sorry...
...حسناً
French?
اللغة الفرنسيّة؟
"Humour" is spelled "h-u-m-o-u-r." You're missing the "h."
،"تهجئة "هيومر" هي "إتش يو إم أو يو آر "تنقصك الـ "إتش
It's not pronounced, though, so I can understand the mistake.
رغم أنّها لا تُنطق هكذا، فأتفهّم الخطأ
That's it! Now I see!
!هكذا إذاً
In which case, the code is...
...في تلك الحالة، الشفرة
I can read it! I can read it!
!أستطيع قراءتها! أستطيع
I can read every single letter!
!قراءة كلّ حرف
That's it! That's definitely where Shinmei-sensei is being held!
ذاك هو! لا بدّ أنّ المكان الذي يُحتجز !فيه شينمي سينسي هو هناك
Inspector!
حضرة لمفتّش
Shinmei-sensei also has dialogue in the eighth chapter we just got!
لدى شينمي سينسي حوار في الفصل الثامن الذي وصلنا للتوّ
What?!
!ماذا؟
This is the scene...
هذا هو المشهد
Oh no! There's no time!
!كلا! الوقت ينفد
If we don't hurry, he and his wife will be--!
...علينا... علينا الإسراع وإلّا سيلقى شينمي سينسي وزوجته
Alright! I'll just do like always...
...حسناً، سأقوم بالمعتاد في تلك الحالة
...and use this Tranquilizer Wristwatch to knock the old guy out!
وأستعمل مسدّس تخدير الساعة لتنويم العمّ
Mori-san. Let me introduce you. This is our chief editor...
...موري-سان، دعني أعرّفك، هذا رئيس دائرة التحرير
I-I missed!
!أ-أخطأت
Whoops! I guess I have no choice!
!كلا! لا خيار أمامي هكذا
Chief! Chief! What's wrong?!
رئيس! رئيس! ما الخطب؟
I'll just have to have him play a detective!
عليّ جعله يلعب دور المتحرّي
Now to set the Voice-Changing Bowtie to use his voice...
حسناً، سأضبط ربطة العنق المبدّلة ...للصوت لتوافق صوته
Let's see...
...لتوافق
Wait a minute! I don't know what he sounds like!
!لحظة! لا أعرف صوته حتّى
Hey, Conan-kun.
كونان-كن
What are you doing down there?
ما الذي تفعله عندك؟
This is bad! There's only one tranquilizer dart!
!هذا سيّئ! تبقّت إبرة تخدير واحدة
I'll have to wait for them to crack the code themselves.
عليّ انتظار أن يحلّ العمّ والبقيّة الشفرة هكذا
But...
...لكن
If we don't hurry, Shinmei-sensei will...!
...إذا لم نسرع، شينمي سينسي سوف
What happened! Please wake up, Chief! Chief!
!ما الخطب؟ استيقظ رجاءً يا رئيس! رئيس
He's snoring. Almost reminds me of "Sleeping Kogoro."
إنّه يشخر، كما لو كان كوغورو النائم
Yes...
أجل
What're you laughing about?
ما الذي يضحكك؟
The chief editor is copying how you sleep!
!يقلّدك رئيس التحرير عند نومك
He seems like he has lots of humor!
(خطر لي أنّه شخص طريف (هيومر
Humor? As always, you know strange words for a kid.
هيومر؟ تعرف كلمات غريبة بالنسبة لصبيّ كالعادة
Those men were talking about it just now!
لكن قالها هذان الرجلان قبل قليل
They were saying stuff about "humour"! Right?
ذكرا شيئاً عن "هيومر"، أليس كذلك؟
Yes...
...بلى
He misspelled the word, so I fixed it for him.
أخطأ في تهجئة كلمة فرنسية، فأصلحتها له
I forgot to add the "h."
"نسيتُ إضافة "إتش
What rubbish.
سخافة
But French people sure are strange!
لكنّ أهل فرنسا غريبون حقّاً
They don't read "h" at the start of words!
لا يقرؤون "إتش" في بداية الكلمات
If they don't say "h," they should remove it from the start!
إذا لن يقرؤوها، فعليهم إزالتها من البداية
Remove it...
...إ-إزالتها
...from the start?
من البداية؟
That reminds me, Shinmei-sensei's character lives in France, right?
بالمناسبة، تعيش شخصيّة شينمي سينسي الظاهرة في الراوية في فرنسا، أليس كذلك؟
Yeah.
بلى
M-Mori-kun... could this be--?
...موري-كن، أيمكن أنّ هذا
Yes... the other key to this code might be the fact
أجل، لعلّ الكلمة المفتاحية الأخرى لهذه الشفرة
that "h" isn't pronounced at the start of words in French.
هي خاصيّة اللغة الفرنسيّة بعدم نطق حرف "إتش" في بداية الكلمات
Silent "h" s!
إتش" الصامتة"
Characters that start with "h"?!
"الكلمات التي تبدأ بـ "إتش
Could it mean to remove the h from ha, hi, hu, he, and ho?!
أي ربما علينا إزالة الكلمات في مجموعة "ها-هِي-هو-هْي"
I see!
فهمت
If it means you have to drop the "h" letter when combining letters,
إذا يُفترض بنا إزالة أحرف مجموعة الهاء "المتشكّلة من "نصفان في القمّة
the "hoka" in the first part works.
فسيكون من المنطقيّ إزالة هوكا" من الجزء الأوّل"
Using all of this to decipher Mr. Shinmei's second scene...
باعتماد قاعدتَي "نصفان في القمّة" و"إتش" الصامتة ...لحلّ شفرة مشهد السيّد شينمي الثاني
...you get "watashi"...
،"واتاشي" و"هوكا" تصبح "واتاشي"
...then "ga"...
،"إي" و"كا" تصبح "غا"
...then "ima"...
،"هي" و"إيما" تصبح "إيما"
...then "i"...
"إي" و"هاكو" تصبح "إي"
...then "ru"...
"ري" و"نو" تصبح "رو"
...then "tokoro"...
"توكورو" و"هان" تصبح "توكورو"
...then "wa"...
"هيتو" و"وا" تصبح "وا"
All together, it's "watashi ga ima i ru tokoro wa"...
بترتيبها، تصبح "واتاشي غا إيما "إي رو توكورو وا
"The place I'm at now"?!
!"المكان الذي أنا فيه الآن"
Wow! It makes a sentence!
!مذهل، أصبحت جملة
I see. He used that "wa" instead of "ha" because of the "h" rule.
"فهمت، استعمل "وا" بدل "ها بسبب قاعدة الهاء
Alright! When you decipher the third scene he's in, you get...
حسنٌ، إذا حللنا شفرة حوار المشهد ...الثالث للسيّد شينمي بهذا النحو
"Ki to shi te i ho te ru"...
"كي تو شي تي إي هو تي رو"
Kido City Hotel? What hotel is that? I've never heard of it.
فندق مدينة كيدو! أيّ فندق هذا؟ لم أسمع به قبلاً
It could be using Hepburn romanization!
لعلّه يستعمل نظام تمثيل هيبورن بالأحرف اللاتينيّة
In which case, "hu" would be "fu."
"في تلك الحالة، لا تكون "فوا "إتش يو"، بل "إف يو"
And if you keep the first "fu," it would combine to make "hai."
"أي لا تزيل "فوا" الأولى، "وفو" و"موكو" يعطيانك "هاي
H-Haido City Hotel?!
!فـ-فندق مدينة هايدو؟
Meaning the fourth set of lines is probably the room number.
مما يعني أنّ الجملة الرابعة تحمل رقم الغرفة غالباً
Let's see...
...حسناً
"2407 go shitsu"...
"اثنان أربعة صفر سبعة غو شيتسو"
"Room 2407"!
!غرفة 2407
Okay! We go straight to Haido City Hotel, Room 2407!
حسناً! توجّهوا مباشرةً للغرفة 2407 !في فندق مدينة هايدو
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
Inspector!
!حضرة المفتّش
What is it, Takagi-kun?!
ما الخطب يا تاكاغي-كن؟
Look at this manuscript! There's more dialogue!
انظر لهذا النصّ رجاءً، لا تزال هنالك تتمة
Oh, this is the eighth chapter that was just faxed here.
هذا الفصل الثامن الذي وصل قبل قليل
Let's see...
...حسناً
"Haya ku..." (hurry)
(هاياكو..." (أسرعوا"
"Ji kan ga nai..." (there's no time)
(جي كان غا ناي" (الوقت ينفد"
"Hurry, there's no time!"
"أسرعوا، الوقت ينفد"
Hey! Hurry it up!
!أنتم! أسرعوا
Haido City Hotel. Follow those police cars.
فندق مدينة هايدو، اتبع سيّارات الشرطة تلك
Hurry!
!أسرع
R-Right!
!حـ-حاضر
Dad... Mom...
...أبي... أمّي
Dad! Mom! Please be okay!
!أبي... أمّي... عسى أن تكونا بخير
They're alive.
إنّهما على قيد الحياة
"There's not much time" can also mean
"يمكن أن تعني "الوقت ينفد
that danger is looming but it's not too late.
أنّ الخطر يقترب، لكن الأوان لم يفت
It's been barely an hour since that manuscript was sent,
بالكاد مضت ساعة مُذ وصل ذاك النصّ بالفاكس
and it's still the middle of the novel.
ولا تزال الرواية في منتصفها
There's a good chance they're alive.
احتمال كونهما على قيد الحياة مرتفع
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
But I don't understand what the captor wants.
لكن لا أفهم هدف الفاعل
Is a crazed fan anxious for the new Det. Samonji series behind this?
أهي فعلة معجب مجنون أراد عملاً جديداً لسلسلة المتحرّي شيمونجي بشدّة؟
No...
كلا، ليس ذلك
Was it an abduction to get a popular writer's money?
أكان اختطافاً لسرقة أجر نصوص روائيّ شهير؟
No, Room 2407 is a suite. That doesn't fit.
كلا، الغرفة 2407 في هذا الفندق هي جناح، لا توافق المبدأ
Then what is the captor after?!
ما هدف الفاعل بالضبط إذاً؟
What is the plan of the person who's forcing Shinmei-sensei to write
ما خطّته بإجبار شينمشي سينسي على كتابة الرواية
even when he can't sign his own name?
بينما لم يعد قادراً على التوقيع حتّى؟
Wait a minute! If he can't sign his name...
...انتظر، إذا لم يستطع التوقيع
...that means he's dictating his story to someone!
فهذا يعني أنّه ينقل الكلمات شفوياً لأحدهم ويجعله يكتب مكانه
Then he's having someone else type it all out,
هذا يعني أنّه ترك شخصاً آخر يكتب النصّ
even when one misplaced letter could ruin the code?!
حيث الإخلال برمز واحد قد يفسد الشفرة؟
That's crazy!
هذا محال
Adding and removing for no reason would make anyone suspicious!
إضافة الرموز وإزالتها بلا معنى سيثير شبهة أيّ أحد
Even if his wife was typing, the person watching would notice!
حتّى لو جعل زوجته تكتب، سيلاحظ الشخص الذي يراقبها
Wait! Hold on! Could this incident actually be--?!
...انتظر
Room 2407... Alright! This is the room!
...الغرفة 2407
The captor may have a weapon! Everyone stay sharp!
!هنالك احتمال بامتلاك الفاعل لأسلحة، كونوا يقظين جميعاً
Umm, can I help you?
المعذرة، أهنالك أمرٌ ما؟
Mom!
!أمّي
Kaori! Why are you here?!
كاوري! لمَ أنتِ هنا؟
Get back, Madam!
!تراجعي يا سيّدة
Freeze! Police!
!لا تتحرّك! نحن الشرطة
Dad! Dad!
!أبي! أبي
Your father passed away just moments ago.
لفظ والدك أنفاسه الأخيرة قبل لحظات
Kaori-san.
كاوري-سان
I called your home many times, but I couldn't get a hold of you.
اتّصلت بمنزلك عدّة مرّات، لكن لم يرد أحد
So you're the one who abducted Mr. Shinmei?
أنت الفاعل الذي اختطف السيّد شينمي إذاً؟
No, I'm...
...كـ-كلا، أنا
He's my husband's personal physician.
إنّه طبيب زوجي الشخصيّ
Then who's the kidnapper?
أين المختطف إذاً؟
There is no kidnapper. If there was, it'd be Shinmei himself.
...لا مختطف هناك، وإذا كان موجوداً
Does that mean the code was--?!
...أكانت تلك الشفرة إذاً
You can't mean--!
أيمكن؟
A fabrication put together by my husband.
كلّها تلفيق من صنع زوجي
B-But why?
لـ-لكن لمَ؟
My husband was always saying this...
...كان يردد دوماً
I, of course, feel happiness when I receive praise for my works,
أشعر بالسعادة عندما أتلقّى ،إطراءً على عملي بالطبع
but in my forty years of writing, there's a happiness I've yet to have.
لكن هنالك سعادة لم أختبرها بعد في أعوام تأليفي الأربعين
Just once, I'd like to see with my own eyes
أريد رؤيتها عياناً ولو لمرّة واحدة
the face of a reader who solves a mystery before I give the solution.
وجه القارئ المشعّ فخراً الذي يحلّ اللغز قبل أن أقدّم الحلّ
He said he wanted to do so before he died,
قال أنّه يريد تحقيق تلك الأمنية قبل موته
so his physician and I helped him write his story here.
لذا ساعدتُه مع الطبيب في الكتابة هنا
Before dying?
قبل موته؟
He lost use of his arms two weeks ago, due to terminal cancer.
فقد القدرة على تحريك ذراعيه قبل أسبوعين بسبب سرطان الأطراف
So that's why his signatures were copies?
لذا كان التوقيع على النصّ منسوخاً؟
I'm sorry for worrying you, Kaori.
آسفة على ترككِ تقلقين يا كاوري
Your father told me not to tell you, to give believability to his code.
أمرني والدك بألّا أخبرك لإعطاء شفرته واقعيّةً أكبر
Forgive your father, and consider it his last selfish act, Kaori...
اعتبريها آخر رغباته الأنانيّة، وسامحيه يا كاوري
Talk about your false alarms...
كانت حادثةً فارغة مثيرة للجلبة بحقّ
Surely he knew a code like that could've caused a big police panic!
يُفترض أنّه عرف أنّ كتابة شفرة كتلك ستستدعي تدخل الشرطة
But he always wrote at the end of his novels
لكنّه كتب في ختام رواياته دوماً
that he wanted to see the proud look of one of his readers.
أنّه يريد رؤية وجه القارئ المشعّ فخراً
He was probably waiting for a reader who figured everything out
فلعلّه كان بانتظار قدوم قارئ اكتشف كلّ شيء
to show up and say, "I solved it!"
"ويأتيه ليقول "حللتُها يا سينسي
But no one ever came.
لكن لم يأت أحد في النهاية
And now that he's gone, the novel will stay unfinished.
وستبقى الرواية بلا نهاية بعدما رحل الآن
I won't let that happen.
لن أسمح بذلك
I'll write the rest of it.
سأكتب تتمتها
I won't shame the name Shinmei Nintaro!
سأحرص على ألّا يتدنّس اسم شينمي نينتارو
Two months after this incident,
،شهران بعد الحادثة
Kaori-san spectacularly completed her father's novel
أتمّت كاوري-سان رواية أبيها ببراعة
and "Halves at the Top" managed to become a bestseller!
"وأصبح مجلّد "نصفان في القمّة من الروايات الأعلى مبيعاً
Naturally, a TV version was soon made and earned great reviews,
اُقتبست منها دراما تلفزيّة بالطبع، ولقت الاستحسان
which led her to enter the writing world!
مما فتح لها باب عالم الكتابة
Although this was because she was as skilled as her father,
،رغم أنّ لارتقاء موهبتها على موهبة أبيها تأثير
the dimwitted detective, tomboy girl, and the cheeky boy in glasses
إلّا أنّ ما لفت الانتباه كانوا مساعدي سامونجي الذين أضيفوا في النصف الثاني للقصّة
I won't say who they were based on...
...لن أقول ممن اُستوحوا
...but I could do without the "cheeky" part.
"لكن لم تكن هنالك حاجة لتضيف "المتبجّح
I'm just a regular Tokyo--
...أنا مجرّد زائرة عاديّة من طوكيو
Sorry!
!آسفان
I get a bad feeling that the killer is playing with us...
يراودني شعورٌ سيّئ بتلاعب القاتل بنا
Bad feeling?
شعور سيّئ؟
Kudo!
!كودو
On the next Conan special--
في الحلقة القادمة الخاصّة من كونان
Next Conan's special hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة الخاصّة من كونان
Rearview mirror.
مرآة خلفيّة
Next episode is a one-hour special.
الحلقة القادمة حلقة خاصّة من ساعة كاملة
Conan goes to Osaka.
سيذهب كونان إلى أوساكا